

Arthur Dias

Full Stack React Developer

React Native React Node **PostgreSQL Javascript Python** HTML **Typescript** Next.js Redux **CSS GraphQL** Nest.js **MongoDB Docker** Git



arthursantos01@gmail.com



github.com/arthurdias01





Bio

React developer and enthusiast focused on acting in the full cycle of the software development process. Experienced in React and Node frameworks and their ecosystems and starting to move on in Python. Currently working in highly available and scalable applications using AWS, Serverless, Docker and PostgreSQL. Comfortable with fast-paced environments, agile ethodologies, test-driven development and clean code.

Work Experience

Coally Agency - Full Stack React Developer Jan 2021 - present

- Developed Apps from scratch building its own requirements
- · Worked to meet client deadlines.
- Planned, developed, tested, deployed, and maintained web applications.
- Effectively translated client requirements into application designs and system requirements.
- Automatized full range of customer's company processes resulting on 3 applications (Dashboard, Mobile and Web) using most recent technologies like React, Next, Firebase, Typescript.
- built e-commerce using wordpress as Backend and NextJS on Front-End.
- REST-API building with NestJS, Docker, PostgreSQL and PrismaORM.
- GraphQL API building with NestJS, Apollo Client, Docker, PostgreSQL.

Recent Work:

Next.js: alluagroweb.vercel.app

iOS App Android App

Work Experience (cont.)

Embraer - Product Development Engineer Jun 2019 - present

- Aerospace Mass Properties Team Military and Executive Programs
- (Former) Structural Design Engineer for KC-390 and Super-Tucano (A-29)
- Masters courses on Aerospace Engineering in partnership with (ITA)

Technological Institute of Aeronautics.

Major concentration on subjects as Aerospace Structures.

System Engineering, Project development. Design Thinking.

embraer.com

ATS4i Engineerig Consulting - Prod. Dev. Engineer Aug 2017 - Mar 2017

- Python Programming for data treatment for Tecplot (Flow visualization)
- Stress analyst for Pneumatic, Fuel and Hydraulic Systems for Embraer Programs:

ERJ-175E2 and ERJ-190E2 Thermal Analysis of components for temperature sealing.

 Stress analysis for Structural supports NX Nastran - Femap Specialist CFD++ Analysis across projects relating (Cabin comfort, VALE - Trains, Ice Optic sensor)
 aerothermalsolutions.co

Engineering Intern, Boeing

May 2014 - Aug 2014

- Python Programming for flight stability.
- Development of a Request of Proposal (Design, and Financial Study for

Production, Scaling and Logistics for Bio-fuels in Aviation) - Design Drone for Surveillance.

- CAD development of landing gear and manufacturing analysis on 3D printing.
- Composite Manufacturing Training
- Systems Engineering Training (Life cycle of product and Project Development)

boeing.com



Soft Skills

Critical Thinking

Focus

Management

Flexibility

Teamwork

Public Speaking

Education

React & React Native, RocketSeat

Jan 2021 - Jul 2022

- ReactJS and Environment Course
- NextJS TDD Styled-Components Redux
- Jest TypeScript React-Query React-Hook-Forms • Sass • Firebase • SOLID
- React Native and Environment Course
 Expo
- Styled-Components React Native Base

React Development, Dev Samurai

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
- Mobile App programming JavaScript, React-Native, NodeJS
- Web Apps programming JavaScript, ReactJS, NextJS, Strapi, NodeJS,

Bootstrap, CSS, SCSS, SASS, Firebase

MSc Aerospace Engineering, Instituto Tecnológico de Aeronáutica

Mar 2018 - Mar 2021 Major in Aerospace Structural Analysis.

BSc Aerospace Engineering, Universidade Federal de Uberlândia

Aug 2010 - Jun 2016 Major in Aerospace Structural Analysis.

BSc Aerospace Engineering, Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University

Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

Dean's List on Spring 2014 of the best Students Major in Aerospace Engineering.



ToolBox

Backend

REST API GraphQL API

Nest.js Node.js

Jest Python/Django

Frontend

HTML5 CSS Javascript
Typescript React
Jest ChakraUI Tailwindcss

DevOps

AWS GCP MySQL

PostgrSQL MongoDB

Git GitHub Docker

Kubernetes Sentry

Projects

Alluagro - Mobile + DashBoard + Web App
Project Scope was to develop three apps and
integrate the whole process of a renting (Farm
Tractors and other Machines) to people who have
a job for it.

To do that I developed:

A DashBoard: React + NextJS + ChakraUI + TypeScript + Firebase

(on it, basically the company can see every machine available posted through another mobile app (built afterwards), follow metrics of the announcements, both for machines as well as for farms needing machine related jobs. It allowed to track progress of each negotiation as well as to track special kinds of reservations where the user could request direct monitoring of the broker company to improve job results). Integration with external API to provide users Farm product prices on Brazil's market.

A Mobile App : React-Native + Expo + Styled-Components + Firebase + TypeScript.

This mobile app (iOS and Android) - allowed users to do the full range of actions such (add machine for renting, add farm for a person with a machine reserve the job, add a partner ad - the partners were basically companies that can provide maintenance for machines). They can also receive notifications sent through the dashboard to a specific or all users or a non-registered user. Integration with external API to provide users Farm product prices on Brazil's market.

a Web App - NextJS + ChakraUI + Firebase + TypeScript
Basically a web-version of the mobile app.

WebApp: alluagroweb.vercel.app

<u>iOS App</u> Android App



ToolBox

Integration

Stripe Paypal

Shopify

CommerceJs

Woocommerce

Twilio

Google Analytics